Dennis Bereznyak

bereznd1@tcnj.edu | 267-391-5741 | Holland, PA

dennisbereznyak.com | linkedin.com/in/dennis-bereznyak | github.com/bereznd1

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative, passionate developer who has been working in the Web field for 3 years, with prior experience learning Web-related skills while studying Interactive Multimedia in college. Recent graduate of the Full Stack Coding Bootcamp at UPENN. Experienced in technologies such as **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **jQuery**, **APIs**, **MySQL**, **MongoDB**, **NodeJS**, **ExpressJS**, & **ReactJS**. Driven to create solutions for tech issues while also focusing on practical details to ensure that these ideas come to fruition.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, AJAX, Firebase, NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, HandlebarsJS, Sequelize, MochaJS & Chai Unit Testing, Git, Heroku, MVC Design Pattern, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, MomentJS, VelocityJS, Mapbox API, AngularJS, Information Architecture, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Wordpress, UI/UX Design, Material Design, Balsamiq, Final Cut Pro

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

1/2018 - 7/2018

Penn LPS Coding BootCamp - Javascript Full Stack Web Development
An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned include HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, HandlebarsJS & ReactJS.

The College of New Jersey, Ewing, New Jersey

5/2017

B.A. - Interactive Multimedia/Minor - Communication Studies | 3.7 GPA | Cum Laude
Thirteen-course Bachelor of Arts degree that combines hands-on instruction using industry-standard tools with in-depth exploration of the cultural impact of digital and interactive technology.

Relevant Coursework: Design Fundamentals for the Web, Mobile Computing, Dynamic Web
Applications, Intro to Interactive Computing, Interactive Design for Developing Communities,
Business Information Systems & Technology

PROJECTS

 $\textbf{BandBase Full Stack App} \mid \textit{ReactJS, MongoDB, Passport, ExpressJS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS} \mid \underline{\textbf{Github}} \mid \underline{\textbf{Live}}$

- Allows bands/artists from around the country to sign up & connect with one another in order to book shows together in a particular area.
- Lead developer of ReactJS, MongoDB, & Routing-related features.
- Developed overall ReactJS structural foundation for the app & handled error validation upon new user signup, as well as user interaction with the database.

Eat-Da-Burger Full Stack App | *NodeJS, ExpressJS, MySQL, HandlebarsJS, jQuery* | **Github** | **Live**

- Allows users to interact with a database, which then affects the information presented to them in their browsers.
- Lead developer.
- Used ExpressJS to set up a server that listens for AJAX requests based on a user's actions, which affects items within a MySQL database.

Dennis Bereznyak

Page 2 of 2

Tune Tracker | Firebase, APIs/AJAX, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap | Github | Live

- Displays work of local musicians on a map to facilitate collaboration amongst local artists.
- Lead developer of API & Firebase-related features.
- Integrated Firebase with Mapbox API to store user input from a form and display it on the map based on users' geographic locations.

LIRI Command Line Node App | NodeJS, APIs/AJAX, JavaScript | Github

- Takes in users' commands and retrieves data based on what they entered.
- Lead developer.
- Programmed Node app to interpret user commands, send AJAX requests to the Twitter, Spotify, & ODMB API's, and then display desired data within terminal window.

EXPERIENCE

New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection | Trenton, NJ

3/2015 - Present

Web Designer

- Improved the design & functionality of the organization's web presence by restructuring various department websites using *HTML*, *CSS*, *jQuery*, *JavaScript*, *Dreamweaver*, & *Photoshop*.
- Implemented improvements to the overall *UI/UX Design* & *Information Architecture* of department websites, allowing the organization to communicate its message online more effectively.
- Managed 5 websites regularly to ensure that they remained up-to-date and free of any technical issues, providing visitors with an efficient interface to retrieve their desired information.

The College of New Jersey | Ewing, NJ

4/2014 - 3/2016

HR Web Assistant

- Implemented improvements to department's **Wordpress** website, which allowed information to be presented more effectively for user consumption.
- Managed web content in a timely manner, which ensured that visitors always received the most up-to-date and relevant information.